<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Yuanpeng&apos;s Blog</title>
    
    
    <description>This website is a virtual proof that I&apos;m awesome</description>
    
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Preferred Orientation and Texture</title>
        <description>
          
          Normally for a powder sample, we are assuming that we have a uniform distribution of orientation of those small crystalline samples, meaning that we have many small crystalline pieces of the sample and their orientation in space is uniform. As such, in the measured powder diffraction pattern, the peak intensities...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-03-preferred_orientation_texture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-03-preferred_orientation_texture/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Notes and Tips for using Docker</title>
        <description>
          
          🏷️ Use git diff in a Docker container Within a Docker container, if we are located in a git repository and try to execute git diff, there will be no problems. However, if the current working directory is not a git repository and we try to execute git diff /full/path/to/git/repo,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-07-16-docker_tips/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-07-16-docker_tips/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dirac Equation</title>
        <description>
          
          Introduction Here in this post, I will be summarizing the derivation of Dirac Equation, following the YouTube video series in Ref. [1-3]. Dirac equation, at the same time beautifully combining quantum mechanics (QM) and special relativity (SR), also infers the existence of electron spin, proposes the existence of antimatter, and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-05-25-dirac_equation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-05-25-dirac_equation/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Amazon AWS S3 setup</title>
        <description>
          
          Introduction Amazon S3 is a cloud service for setting up drives on the cloud, meaning that we can use it for storing and sharing files on the cloud. Compared to the Cloud drives that we commonly see and use every day, such as Dropbox, Google Drive, Proton Drive, Box, and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-03-16-aws_s3_notes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-03-16-aws_s3_notes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Notes on using VSCode</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is a collection of notes for useful setups, tricks and utilities in VSCode, as one of the popular IDEs in the market, along with Sublime Text, Atom, JetBrains, and so many to name. Python Debugger Running the debug mode for coding in IDE is a very convenient feature,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-03-11-vscode_python_debugger/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-03-11-vscode_python_debugger/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mouse gesture on Mac</title>
        <description>
          
          On Windows, we have software like AutoHotkey with which we can define keyboard shortcut for running various actions in a convenient way. With AutoHotkey, we can also define mouse gestures to execute actions quickly. Here in Ref. [1] is provided a zip file containing the AutoHotkey files for some useful...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-03-11-mac_mouse_gesture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-03-11-mac_mouse_gesture/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up a Flarum forum on VPS</title>
        <description>
          
          Set up a VPS and getting a domain for the VPS will not be covered in this blog. Here, I am assuming we have already got our VPS up running. I am using the 1Panel control panel to install the Flarum forum web service, which is one of the most...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-03-07-flarum_setup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-03-07-flarum_setup/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Construct lattice vectors from lattice parameters</title>
        <description>
          
          In crystallography, quite often we would use the 6 lattice parameters to describe the unit cell, namely, a, b, c, \(\alpha\), \(\beta\) and \(\gamma\). In some cases, we would also need to construct those lattice vectors (\(\vec{a}\), \(\vec{b}\) and \(\vec{c}\)) in Cartesian coordinate system. For example, when we want to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-03-04-latt_params_to_latt_vecs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-03-04-latt_params_to_latt_vecs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Photoshop基于图层生成动画</title>
        <description>
          
          将一系列图片导入到Photoshop里，然后基于图层生成动画，即每一个图层为生成动画的一帧，下面给出的是详细的操作步骤，


   
      
   


        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-02-25-ps_make_animation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-02-25-ps_make_animation/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up our own search engine with Yacy</title>
        <description>
          
          The fundamental idea of web searching is through web crawling, critical information about the website and the embedded links in the crawled website can be obtained. Based on the crawling results, a ranking algorithm could be applied, based on which one can search the website using keywords. Nowadays, we get...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-02-04-yacy_setup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-02-04-yacy_setup/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resize Oracle VPS volume</title>
        <description>
          
          When setting up Oracle cloud instance, we would give the instance an initial allocation of volume, and later on we might find that the initial volume size is not enough as we install more and more services into our VPS. In such a situation, we may want to expand the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-01-28-oracle_vps_vol_expand/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-01-28-oracle_vps_vol_expand/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up Dify server on VPS with docker</title>
        <description>
          
          Dify is an LLM application platform which can provide access to various LLM models, tools and applications. With it, we can build our own ChatBot server acting just like ChatGPT. At the backend, it utilizes the LLM services from various providers, such as openAI, Gemini, etc., through API call. In...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-01-27-docker_dify/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-01-27-docker_dify/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up YOURLS on VPS with docker</title>
        <description>
          
          YOURLS is an URL shortening service [1] and we can deploy a local version of the service to our own VPS. Here, I am using the 1Panel service [2] to set up YOURLS – 1Panel is a web-based Linux system management interface with which we can manage our VPS and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-01-15-yourls_docker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-01-15-yourls_docker/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dockerize the ADDIE service</title>
        <description>
          
          Initial Docker Image Build As conventionally, the ADDIE (ADvanced DIffraction Environment, available at addie.ornl.gov) service is deployed on a VPS (specifically, an instance on the ORNL hosted research cloud). The service itself and all the necessary configurations are therefore locked to the VPS machine, making it extremely painful for transfer...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-01-13-dockerize_addie/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-01-13-dockerize_addie/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up services on VPS using docker</title>
        <description>
          
          To set up services on VPS, one could follow the conventional routine to configure the server and set up the services. However, such services would then live natively on the VPS operating system, which is not completely self-contained (e.g., one may need to configure multiple services in the same configuration...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023-12-25-vps_docker_services/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023-12-25-vps_docker_services/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Find out symmetry from RMC fitted supercell</title>
        <description>
          
          In the reverse Monte Carlo (RMC) modeling, there is no constraint of symmetry exerted on the model. Once the initial unit cell is expanded to a supercell, the symmetry constraint will be removed and the model will be purely driven by the data together with some other physical or chemical...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023-10-29-findsym/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023-10-29-findsym/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anaconda token setup for GitHub action</title>
        <description>
          
          Conda package building and deploying (to Anaconda) can be configured in GitHub action so that when a certain action triggers the GitHub action, the conda package will be built and deployed automatically. As part of the setup, the Anaconda token is required in the GitHub settings so that the secure...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023-10-12-token_github_anaconda/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023-10-12-token_github_anaconda/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Size &amp; strain effect and preferred orientation in diffraction</title>
        <description>
          
          Size effect The Bragg equation can be derived based on a simple picture where one can calculate the phase difference between the two sets of incoming and scattered beam corresponding to two scattering center. The fundamental idea is that when the phase difference is the integer multiple of the wavelength,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023-10-09-diff_size_strain/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023-10-09-diff_size_strain/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rustdesk server setup</title>
        <description>
          
          There are several available software in the market for remote control, such as Teamviewer (probably the most well-known one), AnyDesk, etc., including the built-in Windows remote control utility (which is actually already very good especially for the use of local network connection). For cross-platform usage, for sure, Teamviewer is probably...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023-09-10-rustdesk_server/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023-09-10-rustdesk_server/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thermal background in pair distrubtion function (PDF)</title>
        <description>
          
          This post discusses the thermal background of a pair distribution function (PDF), taking the paper by K. Page, et al. [1] as the reference and noting down several aspects that are critical for understanding the topic. The paper was originally reporting an alternative way for coping with the incoherent inelastic...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2023-09-10-pdf_thermal_bkg/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2023-09-10-pdf_thermal_bkg/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
