<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Yuanpeng&apos;s Blog</title>
    
    
    <description>Yuanpeng&apos;s Blog RSS Feed</description>
    
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Local Development of GSAS-II</title>
        <description>
          
          GSAS-II is a powerful software for analyzing the crystallographic structure from diffraction data. It is written in Python, with some underlying routines in Fortran and C++. It is possible to grab the source codes of GSAS-II, develop and test it locally. This post covers the steps to set up the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-03-18-gsasii_dev/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-03-18-gsasii_dev/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Config, Tips and Tricks for Different Operating Systems</title>
        <description>
          
          In this blog, I will be noting down some useful configurations, tips and tricks for all the operating systems that I have been using along the way. I am a big fan of nothing, but at the same time I am also a big fan of everything. So in my...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-03-16-os_configs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-03-16-os_configs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dify Server Maintenance</title>
        <description>
          
          In a previous post (here), I was going through the process of setting up the Dify server with docker. To remind ourselves, Dify is a web-based service with which we can set up own AI agent and workflows, through the APIs of various LLM models. Here in this post, I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-03-16-dify_config/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-03-16-dify_config/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sample and Container geometry for absorption correction</title>
        <description>
          
          When neutrons interact with a measured sample, scattering is one type of the interaction, while absorption is another type. However, for a scattering measurement, the absorption effect ‘steals’ part of the intensity that should belong to the scattering intensity. Therefore, without the correction for the absorption effect, the measured intensity...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-02-12-abs_geo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-02-12-abs_geo/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Use local build of Mantid with Python script</title>
        <description>
          
          Here in the blog, I will covering how to build a local version of Mantid and use it with python. For example, we may have a Python script which uses some Mantid algorithm. On ORNL Analysis cluster, a certain version of Mantid framework has been deployed and we can execute...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-31-mantid_local_python/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-31-mantid_local_python/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up 1panel with Cloudflare</title>
        <description>
          
          1Panel is an open-source web-based control panel for Linux server management. With 1panel, we can manager our server in a visual and convenient manner. Also, it provides application store to install a wide range of web-based applications (with docker as the backend engine). I have my own server hosted on...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-30-1panel_cloudflare/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-30-1panel_cloudflare/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Notes on the development environment setup for RMCProfile</title>
        <description>
          
          This blog is for noting down the technical details about the RMCProfile package building. This is not intended to be a tutorial so it won’t cover all the nitty-gritties. Instead, only some key aspects will be noted down for future reference. Currently, the source code of RMCProfile are hosted on...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-28-rmcprofile_dev_env_gen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-28-rmcprofile_dev_env_gen/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Block the annoying ads on slashdot</title>
        <description>
          
          Slashdot is by far my favourite news collection and sharing platform where people were posting a lot of interesting news covering all sorts of areas, from tech to science, from politics to history, etc. I have been checking the daily feeds on Slashdot literatively on a daily base for quite...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-20-slashdot_block_ads/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-20-slashdot_block_ads/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Development environment setup for RMCProfile on Windows</title>
        <description>
          
          This blog is for noting down the details about setting up the development environment for RMCProfile on Windows machine. The notes here are still based on the conventional way of compiling using make files. There is some work happening in the background now to transfer the compiling to using cmake....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-17-rmcprofile_dev_env_win/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-17-rmcprofile_dev_env_win/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Description of Magnetic Structure with Propogation Vector</title>
        <description>
          
          The magnetic structure sits on top of the nucleus structure and in general, the periodicity of the magnetic structure can be different from that of the nucleus structure. However, the periodicity of the two is indeed related and usually we treat the magnetic structure as a modulation of the nucleus...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-03-prop_vector/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-03-prop_vector/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A brief summary of the early superconductivity development</title>
        <description>
          
          The diagram below is maded out of the nice article in Ref. [1] by Prof. C. Slichter, summarizing the history of the early development of superconductivity. It goes over the discovery of superconducting phenomenon, the early efforts in revealing the reason why such a peculiar phenomenon could ever happen, the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-12-16-superconductivity_summary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-12-16-superconductivity_summary/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up workflows for bidirectional connection between NocoDB and Slack</title>
        <description>
          
          NocoDB is a web-based platform that allows building no-code database, with a spreadsheet-like interface, allowing convenient interaction with the database. Here in this post, I am going to walk through the setup of workflows that connects the NocoDB database with Slack, in a bidirectional manner. Namely, we can build a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-11-07-n8n_slack_nocodb/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-11-07-n8n_slack_nocodb/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up an automated workflow for collecting RSS feeds and send to Gmail</title>
        <description>
          
          Following previous post at Ref. [1], we get a feel about the procedures for setting up an automated workflow with n8n. Here in this post, we try to build another simple workflow and the assumption here is that we have already gone through the post in Ref. [1] for all...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-11-04-n8n_rss_gmail/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-11-04-n8n_rss_gmail/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up an automated workflow for Notion &amp; Slack connection with n8n</title>
        <description>
          
          n8n is a web platform for setting up automated workflows. There are hundreds of apps and software integrations in the platform so that they can be embedded in the automated workflow through APIs. This post goes over the process of setting up a workflow for automatically fetching the to-do list...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-11-03-n8n_notion_slack_workflow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-11-03-n8n_notion_slack_workflow/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips on Wordpress Setup</title>
        <description>
          
          Wordpress is commonly used framework for setting up website without directly and heavily working with HTML or CSS. Here in this blog, I will note down tips for using Wordpress – it keeps record of my problem solving along the way so the whole blog does not come in a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-09-03-wordpress_tips/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-09-03-wordpress_tips/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Output of the Reduced Time-of-Flight Powder Diffraction Bragg Data</title>
        <description>
          
          Fundamentally, the Bragg diffraction data that we will be using for the Rietveld analysis is nothing different as compared to the total scattering data – it is just that for the Bragg data analysis, we focus only on the Bragg peaks, treating the diffuse scattering signal as purely the background....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-30-tof_binning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-30-tof_binning/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>FAQs about Mantid &amp;ndash; Yuanpeng&apos;s Collection</title>
        <description>
          
          Mantid is framework for processing and analyzing neutron and muon scattering data. Eevery now and then, I found myself having difficulties in using some of the algorithms in Mantid and every time I keep forgetting what the solution is. So, in this blog, I will try to note down the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-24-mantid_faq/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-24-mantid_faq/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Van Hove Function</title>
        <description>
          
          The Van Hove function describes the time dependent pair correlation between atoms, \[G(r, t) = \frac{1}{4\pi \rho_0Nr^2}\sum_{i,j}\delta(r - |\vec{r}_i(0) - \vec{r}_j(t)|)\] \(i\) and \(j\) runs over all the \(N\) atoms in the system. \(\vec{r}_i\) refers to the position of the atom \(i\) at time \(t\). The following formula describes the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-22-van_hove_func/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-22-van_hove_func/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Use SSH key with GitLab</title>
        <description>
          
          This post notes down the procedures to go through for setting up the connection to GitLab using SSH key so that we don’t need to bother with the login credentials, which, sometimes can be tedious due to firewall issues, etc. Here, I am using Unix-like OS for demo for the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-19-gitlab_ssh/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-19-gitlab_ssh/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stacking Faults</title>
        <description>
          
          Close packing means that if assuming hard sphere model for atoms, we would have as much dense packing of those hard spheres as possible. Specifically, this refers to the packing of equal spheres (radius being equal). Normally, we have two types of close packing, the hexagonal close packing (HCP) and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-15-stacking_fault/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-15-stacking_fault/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
