<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Yuanpeng&apos;s Blog</title>
    
    
    <description>This website is a virtual proof that I&apos;m awesome</description>
    
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up an automated workflow for Notion &amp; Slack connection with n8n</title>
        <description>
          
          n8n is a web platform for setting up automated workflows. There are hundreds of apps and software integrations in the platform so that they can be embedded in the automated workflow through APIs. This post goes over the process of setting up a workflow for automatically fetching the to-do list...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-11-03-n8n_notion_setup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-11-03-n8n_notion_setup/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips on Wordpress Setup</title>
        <description>
          
          Wordpress is commonly used framework for setting up website without directly and heavily working with HTML or CSS. Here in this blog, I will note down tips for using Wordpress – it keeps record of my problem solving along the way so the whole blog does not come in a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-09-03-wordpress_tips/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-09-03-wordpress_tips/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Output of the Reduced Time-of-Flight Powder Diffraction Bragg Data</title>
        <description>
          
          Fundamentally, the Bragg diffraction data that we will be using for the Rietveld analysis is nothing different as compared to the total scattering data – it is just that for the Bragg data analysis, we focus only on the Bragg peaks, treating the diffuse scattering signal as purely the background....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-30-tof_binning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-30-tof_binning/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>FAQs about Mantid &amp;ndash; Yuanpeng&apos;s Collection</title>
        <description>
          
          Mantid is framework for processing and analyzing neutron and muon scattering data. Eevery now and then, I found myself having difficulties in using some of the algorithms in Mantid and every time I keep forgetting what the solution is. So, in this blog, I will try to note down the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-24-mantid_faq/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-24-mantid_faq/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Van Hove Function</title>
        <description>
          
          The Van Hove function describes the time dependent pair correlation between atoms, \[G(r, t) = \frac{1}{4\pi \rho_0Nr^2}\sum_{i,j}\delta(r - |\vec{r}_i(0) - \vec{r}_j(t)|)\] \(i\) and \(j\) runs over all the \(N\) atoms in the system. \(\vec{r}_i\) refers to the position of the atom \(i\) at time \(t\). The following formula describes the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-22-van_hove_func/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-22-van_hove_func/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Use SSH key with GitLab</title>
        <description>
          
          This post notes down the procedures to go through for setting up the connection to GitLab using SSH key so that we don’t need to bother with the login credentials, which, sometimes can be tedious due to firewall issues, etc. Here, I am using Unix-like OS for demo for the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-19-gitlab_ssh/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-19-gitlab_ssh/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stacking Faults</title>
        <description>
          
          Close packing means that if assuming hard sphere model for atoms, we would have as much dense packing of those hard spheres as possible. Specifically, this refers to the packing of equal spheres (radius being equal). Normally, we have two types of close packing, the hexagonal close packing (HCP) and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-15-stacking_fault/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-15-stacking_fault/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Preferred Orientation and Texture</title>
        <description>
          
          Normally for a powder sample, we are assuming that we have a uniform distribution of orientation of those small crystalline samples, meaning that we have many small crystalline pieces of the sample and their orientation in space is uniform. As such, in the measured powder diffraction pattern, the peak intensities...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-08-03-preferred_orientation_texture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-08-03-preferred_orientation_texture/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Notes and Tips for using Docker</title>
        <description>
          
          🏷️ Use git diff in a Docker container Within a Docker container, if we are located in a git repository and try to execute git diff, there will be no problems. However, if the current working directory is not a git repository and we try to execute git diff /full/path/to/git/repo,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-07-16-docker_tips/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-07-16-docker_tips/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dirac Equation</title>
        <description>
          
          Introduction Here in this post, I will be summarizing the derivation of Dirac Equation, following the YouTube video series in Ref. [1-3]. Dirac equation, at the same time beautifully combining quantum mechanics (QM) and special relativity (SR), also infers the existence of electron spin, proposes the existence of antimatter, and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-05-25-dirac_equation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-05-25-dirac_equation/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Amazon AWS S3 setup</title>
        <description>
          
          Introduction Amazon S3 is a cloud service for setting up drives on the cloud, meaning that we can use it for storing and sharing files on the cloud. Compared to the Cloud drives that we commonly see and use every day, such as Dropbox, Google Drive, Proton Drive, Box, and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-03-16-aws_s3_notes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-03-16-aws_s3_notes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Notes on using VSCode</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is a collection of notes for useful setups, tricks and utilities in VSCode, as one of the popular IDEs in the market, along with Sublime Text, Atom, JetBrains, and so many to name. Python Debugger Running the debug mode for coding in IDE is a very convenient feature,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-03-11-vscode_python_debugger/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-03-11-vscode_python_debugger/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mouse gesture on Mac</title>
        <description>
          
          On Windows, we have software like AutoHotkey with which we can define keyboard shortcut for running various actions in a convenient way. With AutoHotkey, we can also define mouse gestures to execute actions quickly. Here in Ref. [1] is provided a zip file containing the AutoHotkey files for some useful...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-03-11-mac_mouse_gesture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-03-11-mac_mouse_gesture/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up a Flarum forum on VPS</title>
        <description>
          
          Set up a VPS and getting a domain for the VPS will not be covered in this blog. Here, I am assuming we have already got our VPS up running. I am using the 1Panel control panel to install the Flarum forum web service, which is one of the most...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-03-07-flarum_setup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-03-07-flarum_setup/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Construct lattice vectors from lattice parameters</title>
        <description>
          
          In crystallography, quite often we would use the 6 lattice parameters to describe the unit cell, namely, a, b, c, \(\alpha\), \(\beta\) and \(\gamma\). In some cases, we would also need to construct those lattice vectors (\(\vec{a}\), \(\vec{b}\) and \(\vec{c}\)) in Cartesian coordinate system. For example, when we want to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-03-04-latt_params_to_latt_vecs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-03-04-latt_params_to_latt_vecs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Photoshop基于图层生成动画</title>
        <description>
          
          将一系列图片导入到Photoshop里，然后基于图层生成动画，即每一个图层为生成动画的一帧，下面给出的是详细的操作步骤，


   
      
   


        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-02-25-ps_make_animation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-02-25-ps_make_animation/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up our own search engine with Yacy</title>
        <description>
          
          The fundamental idea of web searching is through web crawling, critical information about the website and the embedded links in the crawled website can be obtained. Based on the crawling results, a ranking algorithm could be applied, based on which one can search the website using keywords. Nowadays, we get...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-02-04-yacy_setup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-02-04-yacy_setup/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resize Oracle VPS volume</title>
        <description>
          
          When setting up Oracle cloud instance, we would give the instance an initial allocation of volume, and later on we might find that the initial volume size is not enough as we install more and more services into our VPS. In such a situation, we may want to expand the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-01-28-oracle_vps_vol_expand/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-01-28-oracle_vps_vol_expand/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up Dify server on VPS with docker</title>
        <description>
          
          Dify is an LLM application platform which can provide access to various LLM models, tools and applications. With it, we can build our own ChatBot server acting just like ChatGPT. At the backend, it utilizes the LLM services from various providers, such as openAI, Gemini, etc., through API call. In...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-01-27-docker_dify/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-01-27-docker_dify/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up YOURLS on VPS with docker</title>
        <description>
          
          YOURLS is an URL shortening service [1] and we can deploy a local version of the service to our own VPS. Here, I am using the 1Panel service [2] to set up YOURLS – 1Panel is a web-based Linux system management interface with which we can manage our VPS and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-01-15-yourls_docker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-01-15-yourls_docker/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
