<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Yuanpeng&apos;s Blog</title>
    
    
    <description>Yuanpeng&apos;s Blog RSS Feed</description>
    
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Use Netbird for Setting up a Peer-to-Peer Private Network</title>
        <description>
          
          Before we dive into the topic, I am sharing several of my typical needs that lead me to learn about something like netbird. From my home network, I want to connect to the machines inside the firewall of my work place. For some companies, it may be possible to install...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-06-23-netbird_notes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-06-23-netbird_notes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Notes on Selection Rule for Transition between Energy Levels</title>
        <description>
          
          When a physical system is absorbing or emitting electromagnetic radiation, there will be a transition happening between the quantum energy levels of the system. The selection rule determines whether or not such a transition can happen. It is a typical topic in quantum mechanics textbook and it is not the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-06-15-selection_rule/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-06-15-selection_rule/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Windows in Docker</title>
        <description>
          
          Yes, now we can run Windows in a docker container. That means we can access the Windows operating system from the web, thanks to the Windows docker image provided in Ref. [1]. Based on the instructions provided in Ref. [1], here follows is my docker compose file to start up...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-06-14-windows_in_docker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-06-14-windows_in_docker/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Time-Based One-Time Password Generation Programmingly</title>
        <description>
          
          Today is May-20-2025. In Chinese, the pronunciation of ‘May-20’ is similar to ‘I love you’ so today is usually the day to express the love between boyfriend and girlfriend, wife and husband. Love you! My beloved Xin! Nowadays, more and more web services are implementing the two-factor authentication (2FA, or...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-05-20-totp_code_gen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-05-20-totp_code_gen/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Local Development Environment Setup for NOVA</title>
        <description>
          
          This post will go over the steps for setting up the local development for nova, which is a frontend interface platform at ORNL that interacts with the backend Galaxy workflow platform. First, set up the conda environment, [CONDA_SUBDIR=osx-64] conda create -n pdiffvis -c conda-forge -c mantid python=3.10 mantid poetry conda...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-05-09-nova_dev/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-05-09-nova_dev/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Configure a Local Mantid Live Reduction Service</title>
        <description>
          
          Here in this post, I am writing down notes regarding the configuration of a Mantid live reduction service locally. By ‘locally’, I mean the service can be managed by a local user, instead a system-wise one for which the management would require a sudo privilege. Relevant scripts are stored in...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-04-21-mantid_livered/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-04-21-mantid_livered/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Local Development of GSAS-II -- New Instructions</title>
        <description>
          
          Here in this post, I will put down the instructions for setting up the local developing environment for GSAS-II. See the legacy instructions in my previous post here for the old version of the source codes. Conda Environment Setup conda create -n gsasii_dev conda activate gsasii_dev conda install python numpy...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-04-21-gsasii_dev_new/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-04-21-gsasii_dev_new/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Local Development of GSAS-II -- Deprecated Instructions</title>
        <description>
          
          GSAS-II is a powerful software for analyzing the crystallographic structure from diffraction data. It is written in Python, with some underlying routines in Fortran and C++. It is possible to grab the source codes of GSAS-II, develop and test it locally. This post covers the steps to set up the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-03-18-gsasii_dev/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-03-18-gsasii_dev/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Config, Tips and Tricks for Different Operating Systems</title>
        <description>
          
          In this blog, I will be noting down some useful configurations, tips and tricks for all the operating systems that I have been using along the way. I am a big fan of nothing, but at the same time I am also a big fan of everything. So in my...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-03-16-os_configs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-03-16-os_configs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dify Server Maintenance</title>
        <description>
          
          In a previous post (here), I was going through the process of setting up the Dify server with docker. To remind ourselves, Dify is a web-based service with which we can set up own AI agent and workflows, through the APIs of various LLM models. Here in this post, I...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-03-16-dify_config/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-03-16-dify_config/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sample and Container geometry for absorption correction</title>
        <description>
          
          When neutrons interact with a measured sample, scattering is one type of the interaction, while absorption is another type. However, for a scattering measurement, the absorption effect ‘steals’ part of the intensity that should belong to the scattering intensity. Therefore, without the correction for the absorption effect, the measured intensity...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-02-12-abs_geo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-02-12-abs_geo/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Use local build of Mantid with Python script</title>
        <description>
          
          Here in the blog, I will covering how to build a local version of Mantid and use it with python. For example, we may have a Python script which uses some Mantid algorithm. On ORNL Analysis cluster, a certain version of Mantid framework has been deployed and we can execute...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-31-mantid_local_python/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-31-mantid_local_python/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up 1panel with Cloudflare</title>
        <description>
          
          1Panel is an open-source web-based control panel for Linux server management. With 1panel, we can manager our server in a visual and convenient manner. Also, it provides application store to install a wide range of web-based applications (with docker as the backend engine). I have my own server hosted on...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-30-1panel_cloudflare/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-30-1panel_cloudflare/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Notes on the development environment setup for RMCProfile</title>
        <description>
          
          This blog is for noting down the technical details about the RMCProfile package building. This is not intended to be a tutorial so it won’t cover all the nitty-gritties. Instead, only some key aspects will be noted down for future reference. The ARM64 package is built on my personal VPS...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-28-rmcprofile_dev_env_gen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-28-rmcprofile_dev_env_gen/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Block the annoying ads on slashdot</title>
        <description>
          
          Slashdot is by far my favourite news collection and sharing platform where people were posting a lot of interesting news covering all sorts of areas, from tech to science, from politics to history, etc. I have been checking the daily feeds on Slashdot literatively on a daily base for quite...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-20-slashdot_block_ads/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-20-slashdot_block_ads/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Development environment setup for RMCProfile on Windows</title>
        <description>
          
          This blog is for noting down the details about setting up the development environment for RMCProfile on Windows machine. The notes here are still based on the conventional way of compiling using make files. There is some work happening in the background now to transfer the compiling to using cmake....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-17-rmcprofile_dev_env_win/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-17-rmcprofile_dev_env_win/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Description of Magnetic Structure with Propogation Vector</title>
        <description>
          
          The magnetic structure sits on top of the nucleus structure and in general, the periodicity of the magnetic structure can be different from that of the nucleus structure. However, the periodicity of the two is indeed related and usually we treat the magnetic structure as a modulation of the nucleus...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-01-03-prop_vector/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-01-03-prop_vector/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A brief summary of the early superconductivity development</title>
        <description>
          
          The diagram below is maded out of the nice article in Ref. [1] by Prof. C. Slichter, summarizing the history of the early development of superconductivity. It goes over the discovery of superconducting phenomenon, the early efforts in revealing the reason why such a peculiar phenomenon could ever happen, the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-12-16-superconductivity_summary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-12-16-superconductivity_summary/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up workflows for bidirectional connection between NocoDB and Slack</title>
        <description>
          
          NocoDB is a web-based platform that allows building no-code database, with a spreadsheet-like interface, allowing convenient interaction with the database. Here in this post, I am going to walk through the setup of workflows that connects the NocoDB database with Slack, in a bidirectional manner. Namely, we can build a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-11-07-n8n_slack_nocodb/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-11-07-n8n_slack_nocodb/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Set up an automated workflow for collecting RSS feeds and send to Gmail</title>
        <description>
          
          Following previous post at Ref. [1], we get a feel about the procedures for setting up an automated workflow with n8n. Here in this post, we try to build another simple workflow and the assumption here is that we have already gone through the post in Ref. [1] for all...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2024-11-04-n8n_rss_gmail/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2024-11-04-n8n_rss_gmail/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
